Gross, James NLRB Audiocassettes /4057 AV
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
James Gross NLRB Audiocassettes
1981-1989
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Gross, James
/4057 AV
3.67 cubic feet
3.3 linear ft.
Audiovisual materials.
Audio of James Gross's interviews with Melvin Welles, D. Pollitt, Thomas Miller, Jr., Ed Miller and Frank McCulloch.
7919178
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, November 14, 2012
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, September 23, 2016
Biographical / Historical
James Gross (1933-) was raised near Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. He graduated from La Salle University with a Bachelor of Science in 1956. Gross received his Ph.D. from the University of Wisconsin in 1962.
He taught as an assistant professor at Holy Cross College from 1960 to 1966 before joining the faculty at Cornell. He was named an associate professor in 1968 and a full professor in 1975.
Gross's three-volume history of the National Labor Relations Board has been called both authoritative and exhaustive. The Reshaping of the National Labor Relations Board: National Labor Policy in Transition, 1937-1947, the second volume of his trilogy, won the Philip Taft Labor History Book Award in 1983.
He is a member of the National Academy of Arbitrators, the American Arbitration Associaiton, and the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service.
Gross received a grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities, and in 2007 was Fulbright Visiting Research Chair in Corporate Social Responsibility at McGill University in Canada.
Biographical / Historical
NLRB 1935-2010
The National Labor Relations Board is proud of its 75-year history of enforcing the National Labor Relations Act, the primary law governing relations between employers and employees in the private sector. On July 5, 1935, President Franklin Roosevelt signed the Act into law, stating that the law sought to achieve "common justice and economic advance." Starting in the Great Depression and continuing through World War II and the economic growth and challenges that followed, the NLRB has worked to guarantee the rights of employees to bargain collectively, if they choose to do so.
Scope and Contents
Audio of James Gross's interviews with Melvin Welles, D. Pollitt, Thomas Miller, Jr., Ed Miller and Frank McCulloch.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /4057: James Gross NLRB Files /4057 P: James Gross NLRB Photographs /4079: James Gross Additional Files /4124: James Gross Papers, Additional NLRB Research Files /4166: James Gross Additional NLRB Research Files /4186: James Gross Additional Research Files /4190: James Gross Additional Research Files /4232: James Gross Collection of NLRB 60th Annual Conference Files 5697: James A. Gross Arbitration Files 5959: James Gross Additional Arbitration Files
Gross, James A., 1933-; McCulloch, Frank; Miller, Thomas; Miller, Ed; Welles, Melvin; National Labor Relations Bureau (U.S.)
7919178
- Melvin Welles Interview, 1 (Box 2)
  Scope and Contents
  Tape 1
- Melvin Welles Interview, 1 (Box 3)
  Tape 2
- Melvin Welles Interview, 1 (Box 4)
  Tape 3
- Melvin Welles Interview, 1 (Box 5)
  Tape 4
- Melvin Welles Interview, 1 (Box 6)
  Tape 5
- D. Pollitt Interview, 1 (Box 7)
  tape 1
- D. Pollitt Interview, 1 (Box 8)
  tape 2
- D. Pollitt Interview, 1 (Box 9)
  tape 3
- D. Pollitt Interview, 1 (Box 10)
  tape 4
- Thomas Miller, Jr. Interview, 1989; 1 (Box 11)
  (9/1989) - tape 1
- Thomas Miller, Jr. Interview, 1989; 1 (Box 12)
  (9/1989) - tape 2
- Ed Miller Interview, 1984; 1 (Box 13)
  10/23/1984 - tape 1 (side 1/2)
- Ed Miller Interview, 1984; 1 (Box 14)
  10/23/1984 - tape 2 (side 3/4)
- Frank McCulloch First Interview, 1981; 1 (Box 15)
  12/7/1981. side 1/2
- Frank McCulloch First Interview, 1981; 1 (Box 16)
  12/7/1981. side 3/4
- Frank McCulloch First Interview, 1981; 1 (Box 17)
  12/7/1981. side 5/6
- Frank McCulloch First Interview, 1981; 1 (Box 18)
  12/7/1981. side 7/8
- Frank McCulloch First Interview, 1981; 1 (Box 19)
  12/7/1981. side 9/10
- Frank McCulloch First Interview, 1981; 1 (Box 20)
  12/7/1981. side 11/12
- Frank McCulloch Second Interview, 1989; 1 (Box 21)
  9/1989, tape 1
- Frank McCulloch Second Interview, 1989; 1 (Box 22)
  9/1989, tape 2
- Frank McCulloch Second Interview, 1989; 1 (Box 23)
  9/1989, tape 3
- Frank McCulloch Second Interview, 1989; 1 (Box 24)
  9/1989, tape 4
- Frank McCulloch Second Interview, 1989; 1 (Box 25)
  9/1989, tape 5
- Frank McCulloch Second Interview, 1989; 1 (Box 26)
  9/1989, tape 6
- Frank McCulloch Second Interview, 1989; 1 (Box 27)
  9/1989, tape 7
- Frank McCulloch Second Interview, 1989; 1 (Box 28)
  9/1989, tape 8
- Frank McCulloch Second Interview, 1989; 1 (Box 29)
  9/1989, tape 9
- Frank McCulloch Second Interview, 1989; 1 (Box 30)
  9/1989, tape 10
- Frank McCulloch Second Interview, 1989; 1 (Box 31)
  9/1989, tape 11
- Audio digitized from the collection. (Box 32)